{
    "id": "86cdf2a12e9e4ca7838d91462e0df3b2",
    "title": "Relative Pronouns Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I know the place …………………….. he lives.",
            "description": "When we separate the clauses we get:\r\nI know the place. He lives there.\r\nThe relative pronoun where replaces place words like there.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "where",
                "there"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He is the man ……………………….. rescued my sister.",
            "description": "When we separate the clauses we get:\r\nHe is the man. He rescued my sister.\r\nThe relative pronoun who replaces words like he, she and they.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He never does anything ………………………….. is silly.",
            "description": "The relative pronoun that is preferred after words like all, any or anything.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "what",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Here is the book …………………….. you want.",
            "description": "When we separate the clauses we get:\r\nHere is the book. You want it.\r\nThe relative pronoun that can replace words like he, she and it. \r\n",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "what",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "People ………………………. live in glass houses should not throw stones.",
            "description": "The relative pronoun who is used to talk about people.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Any student ………………………… fails to do the homework will be punished.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He laughs best ……………………….. laughs last.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "This is the reason ………………………… he came late.",
            "description": "We can use that or why after reason.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "why",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The explanation …………………………. he gave us was not satisfactory.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "which",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The houses in …………………………… the Burmese live are generally built of bamboo.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "there",
                "where",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He met a girl ……………………….. eyes were blue.",
            "description": "The relative pronoun whose replaces words like his or her.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whose",
                "who's"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The author lives in that cottage ……………………….. overlooks the lake.",
            "description": "That and which can both refer to things in identifying relative clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "there",
                "where"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}